Windmuller, John P. Additional Papers /4065
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
John P. Windmuller Additional Papers
1951-1961
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Windmuller, John P.
/4065
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
7980440
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, January 15, 2016
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, September 26, 2016
Biographical / Historical
John P. Windmuller (December 4, 1923 December 2, 2003) was Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations at Cornell University's New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
A graduate of the University of Illinois (BA, 1948) and Cornell University's ILR School (PhD, 1951), Windmuller joined the Cornell University faculty in 1951. He was appointed the Martin P. Catherwood Professor of Industrial and Labor Relations in 1983. He was named professor emeritus in 1987.
An expert in the study of international and comparative labor relations, Windmuller authored many books and reports on the topic, among them Collective Bargaining in Industrial Market Economies: A Reappraisal (ILO, 1987) and Labor Relations in the Netherlands (Ithaca: Cornell, 1969). With Alan Gladstone, he edited Employer Associations and Industrial Relations: A Comparative Study (New York: Oxford, 1984).
See the Cornell University Faculty Memorial Statement for Professor John Windmuller: http://hdl.handle.net/1813/18116
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /3028: John P. Windmuller Records /4046: ILR School Historical School Documents /4158: John P. Windmuller Additional Papers 5033: International Communist Front Organizations Monthly Publications and Miscellaneous Publications 5272: International Confederation of Free Trade Unions Asian Regional Organization Records 5586m: International Trade Secretariats Miscellaneous Documents 5725: International Communist Front Organization Additional Publications
Windmuller, John P.
7980440
- Romualdi File (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Labor Dept. Advisory Subcommittee (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Labor Dept. Advisory Committee (Box 1, Folder 3)
- AFL-CIO International Affairs Committee (Box 1, Folder 4)
- AFL-CIO Inter-American Affairs Committee (Box 1, Folder 5)
- FOA Labor Committee (Box 1, Folder 6)
- FOA Labor Subcommittee (Box 1, Folder 7)
- FOA Labor Committee Documents (Box 1, Folder 8)
- CIO -- Foreign Policy (Box 1, Folder 9)
- CIO - Spain + Latin America (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Latin American Correspondence (Pre-1970) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- CIO----WFTU (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Newspaper Clippings (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Outline -- Collective Bargaining (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Outline -- Labor History + Administration (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Senior Seminar -- ILR 482 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Inter-Am. Labor Bulletin - Jan. 1961 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Inter-Am. Labor Bulletin - Jan. 1961 - Cont. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Inter-Am. Labor Bulletin - Feb. 1957-Dec. 1960, 1957-1960 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Inter-Am. Labor Bulletin - Jan. 1954-Dec. 1956, 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Inter-Am. Labor Bulletin - Feb. 1951-Dec. 1953, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)